在我移动这东西之前我会再花一秒钟
I will spend one more second before I shift this thing and
转到下一个。
move on to the next one.
除非你在我们继续之前有任何愿望。
Unless you have any wishes here before we move on.
但是我们在这里还能做什么，我们实际上可以解决这个问题，对吗？
But what else we can do here we can actually step this out, right?
所以我们可以进行解释器测试。
So we can interpreter test.
可以在这里做 interpretTest，和
Could do interpretTest here, and
而不是 dbToTask 怎么样 dbToId，对吧？
instead of dbToTask what about dbToId, right?
代替 consoleToTask，consoleToId 怎么样？
Instead of consoleToTask, what about consoleToId?
我们可以在这里编写一些函数。
And we could write a little couple functions here.
所以我们有 consoleToTask，而不是实际的参数 ID，
So we have consoleToTask, where Instead of actually params ID,
而不是实际阅读问题以获取输入，
instead of actually reading the question getting the input,
我们可以说 Id of，这将是一个函数
we can say Id of, it's going to be a function here of
不管问题是什么 q 说 q 的答案。
whatever the question was q say answer to q.
好吧，别管我了。
All right, get this out of my way.
对于在线的人来说，这一定是非常令人沮丧的。
It's gotta be horribly frustrating for people online.
很抱歉这些弹出窗口到处都很酷。
Sorry about these pop-ups everywhere cool.
所以有问题。
So there is question.
让我用换句话说 [笑] 对一些实际的东西进行评级。
Let me actually break this out in other word [LAUGH] rating some actual stuff.
这里的输出会发生什么，
And what's gonna happen here for the output,
好吧，我有一些，我有一根绳子
this well, I've got some, I've got a string and
我可以将字符串写为 Id。
I can do Id of writing the string as.
好吧，继续这样做，记住我要进行插值
All right keep doing that, remember I'm gonna be interpolating so
你可以看到发生了什么。
you could see what's going on.
很酷，所以我们正在做的是，返回一个记录正在发生的事情的 ID。
Cool, so what we're doing is, returning an ID that kind of logs what's happening.
它实际上并没有写入屏幕。
And it's not actually writing to the screen.
我们正在取回数据。
We're getting data back.
如果我们对Id做DB，我们也可以这样做
If we do DB to Id, we can do the same
关于保存的事情，糟糕。
thing on save and an all oops.
这需要我们的桌子两次。
And that takes our table both times.
关于记录查询的提示。
Tip on a record query.
然后再次，
And again,
保存我们的桌子。
saving our table.
在这里我们会找到所有
And here we'll finding all
在带有查询的表中。
in the table with a query.
太好了，看看我们的测试解释器会发生什么。
Great, see what happens here with our test interpreter.
简直炸了
Just blows up.
[笑] 我还在分叉。
[LAUGH] I'm still forking it.
[笑] 所以我和我们只是要提取。
[LAUGH] So Id and we're just going to extract.
然后从那里开始，我们将递归地运行
And then from there, we're going to run our recursively
看看会发生什么。
on that and see what happens.
埃迪不好，我得把它带进来。
Eddie's not fine, I gotta bring it in.
嘘嘘。
Boo Boo.
这是一天中的时间，这只是一次又一次的空气。
This is about the time of the day where this is just gonna be air after after air.
F 不是函数和解释测试，只是不知道 f 在哪里。
F is not a function and interpretTest, just don't even know where f is.
所以我们要运行它。
So we're gonna run that.
我们回到，&gt;&gt; Ruby 启动和数据函数。
Are we back to, &gt;&gt; Ruby start and data function.
&gt;&gt; 所以我们正在提取 Id 中的任何内容。
&gt;&gt; So we're extracting whatever is in the Id.
记住在我们做出这个承诺之前，这些事情将会发生
And remember before we made this promise that these things were going to be
返回就像，好吧，我认为他们正在返回延续的任务。
returning like, well, I think they're returning tasks of the continuation.
当我们运行这些东西时
And as we run these things and
链接这些东西，我们实际上正在运行和链接免费的 mon 广告，
chain these things, we're actually running and chaining the free mon ad,
这被解释为另一种结果。
which is being interpreted into a different kind of result.
所以应该仍然像 dbSave 和
So that should still hold like dbSave and
现在所有这些都只是将它们变成了 ID。
all that is just turning them into Ids now.
我想我只是，我现在很困惑 f 是什么。
I think I'm just, I'm confused what f is right now.
这将是最后的小事。
This will be the last little thing.
看看这个console.logf。
Just look at this console.logf.
再一次，回到我应该把这个放在首位，对吧？
Once again, back to I should just left this in the first place, right?
[声音] 好的，f 是什么？
[SOUND] Okay, what is f?
F 是未定义的路由器路由。
F is undefined router route.
我们走了。
There we go.
看看发生了什么。
See what happened.
我没有正确解释我的问题是答案和
I didn't interpret correctly on my question is the answer to and
应该是路线
it's supposed to be a route.
只是为了好玩，让我们做正确的事，让我们看看会发生什么。
Just for fun let's just do right let's see what happens.
[声音] [笑] 炸毁了堆栈。
[SOUND] [LAUGH] Blew the stack.
[笑]但你可以看到，它确实在解释它。
[LAUGH] But you can see, it is indeed interpreting it.
我们只需要做更多的工作。
We just have to do a little bit more work arounds.
好的，既然我们不去任务和做这个问答界面，
Okay, now that we're not going to task and doing this question answer interface,
我该如何模拟。
how do I mock out.
我想在我们关闭之前我接下来要做的是说好，
I think what I would do next before we shut this is to say well,
我对每一个问题都有答案，有点预装在我的测试框架中，
I have a answer to every question, kinda pre canned in my test framework,
我会查一下我对立方体的答案表。
and I'll just look up my answers table to the cube.
然后发生的事情是我们实际上是
Then what's happening is we're actually
当我提出正确的问题时，写回有效路线。
writing the valid route back when I asked the right questions.
打印应该可以工作，然后很有趣，
Printing should work and then it's interesting,
我们可能没有注意到的是固定数据点是递归数据
something we may not have noticed is the fixed data point is a recursive data
正如我们所见，它的结构刚刚炸毁了这个甲板。
structure as we see it just blew this deck.
我们只是一遍又一遍地调用它，对吗？
We just call this again and again and again right?
停止免费 mon 广告的方法，你有几个构造函数
And the way to stop a free mon ad, you have a few constructors
在这里，电梯 f 把你放在了自由里，但你也有纯洁。
in here lift f puts you in a free, but you also have pure.
而 pure 是一种让你的构造函数结束的方法，它只会停止。
And pure is a way to make your constructor that's the end and it will just stop.
所以我们可以这样做，但我们不会，你知道，它就在那里。
So we could do that, but we wont, you know, it's there.
这是一个很酷的方法。
And this is a cool way to do it.
我们已经编写了一个应用程序，而且我们已经根据免费的 monad 编写了它。
We've written an app and we've written it in terms of free monads.
我们已经制作了多个口译员。
And we've made multiple interpreters.
所以也一样。
So all as well.
好的，我们对此有任何疑问吗？
Okay, do we have any questions on this?
&gt;&gt; 您可以向上滚动到顶部吗？
&gt;&gt; Can you scroll back up to the top?
我确定我只是，它是由我们添加的最后一件事触发的。
I'm sure I just, it was triggered by the one of the last things that we added.
我们必须引入 Id monad。
We had to pull in what was the Id monad.
是的，定点类型。
Yes, the fixed points type.
本质上，我们必须有某种退出条件。
Essentially, we have to have some sort of exit condition.
&gt;&gt; 是的。 &gt;&gt; 循环。
&gt;&gt; Yes. &gt;&gt; The loops.
所以无论是类型还是逻辑结构或
So whether that's a type or it's a logical construction or
一些东西，我们需要有某种方式来提示递归。
something, we need to have some way of cueing the recursion to.
&gt;&gt; 没错，实际上就是这样。
&gt;&gt; Exactly, and actually that's exactly.
所以你从修复开始。
So you start with fix.
我们有这些函子要么有不动点函子，要么没有。
And we have these functors have either have a fixed point functor or you don't.
列表是一个不动点函子，
A list is a fixed point functor,
因为它会在列表中的列表中包含一个列表，直到您点击 null，对吗？
cuz it will have a list inside a list inside a list until you hit null, right?
而 null 是不动点。
And null is the fixed point.
fix 的工作方式是将自己注入到这些东西之间。
The way fix works is it injects itself in between each of these things.
而免费做完全相同的事情只是为您提供纯粹的停止。
And free does the exact same thing just provides you with pure to stop.
所以你有你的函子，然后你去自由你要函子和
So you have your functor and then you go to free you're going to functor and
得到自由，然后你终于达到了你的纯洁，然后你就停下来了。
get free and then you finally hit your pure and you stop.
所以它给你它只是固定的端点。
So it gives you it's just fixed with an endpoint to it.